[Music]
hello and welcome to the junkyard love
podcast
at what age do we learn how to have
better conversations
at what age should we learn to have
better conversations with ourselves
[Music]
hey folks it's me the batman
and welcome to the junkyard love podcast
today we have
ian and shay of camp reeducation i'm
super pumped for the episode but before
we get going i'm going to give you a
recommendation
today it's in the form of a documentary
that documentary is on
netflix and it's called the social
dilemma you absolutely have to watch
the staying documentary you have to
change your life accordingly
if you haven't drank any water today get
some water take care of yourself
stretch your body unfurl your brow
relax your shoulders let's get to it
the junkyard love podcast featuring camp
re-education
ian and shea let's go
we kind of figured we would keep this um
kind of conversational-ish and casual i
thought it was cool that you guys were
talking about uh
you're now doing adult meeting people
you're uh
meeting new friends that way so we can
almost even treat it like this just be
inquisitive with one another
um we could start with tell us about
camp free education and then if you guys
could squeeze some of your background as
as just individuals like what's led you
to this
too we'll get it going tell me about
camp free education
sure um [__] i feel like i always hand
this question off to you
and you always do a really good job do
you want to do that here as well that's
so funny because i feel like i always
hand it off to you
because i never want to start but i love
that you offered the baton to me so i
will take it um
okay yeah so camper education started uh
ian had suggested it
months and months ago and it took us
forever to finally get the ball rolling
but
and i think the reason for that was
because he originally suggested the name
hamster fight
which made no sense to me and
i didn't quite the concept wasn't
totally there uh but now the concept
is uh we we do two-week immersions into
various topics and we try and
dive as deep as humanly possible while
still
currently having jobs um
we we've done crazy things so far we did
uh
we've done micro dosing that was
actually a four week immersion uh we've
done
makeup we've done podcasts we've done
reality tv
we're in the middle of one on friendship
right now which is already like such
a crazy subject it it it's this one of
these subjects that sounds so simple
and then as soon as you start digging
into it you on on you peel back the
layers of that onion you realize
how complicated and intricate
it really is um but yeah i guess about
myself like
i ian and i both met in we met in
gainesville florida
uh living together we we met in
existentialism class
and uh like within two we even have to
explain that at some point
i i always make the joke we met in the
most like pretentious way possible
in a college existentialism class like
there's no worse way to meet someone and
like
how did you youtube meet because as soon
as that comes up you're like ah here we
go
uh we met in an existentialism class and
that is like
a trigger for people to leave the
conversation they're like yeah this
this conversation is over man i can
already tell it i don't want to talk to
you
see you later well i'm still here for it
you're like oh no my uh my zoom is uh
it's weird i can't hear you guys
it's going through a tunnel i don't know
[Laughter]
yeah i i feel like you guys have good
chemistry going
yeah i don't know how that worked out
because we we uh we really i didn't
really like ian at
all at first ian ian's just such a funny
guy
and he can command a room and uh
still now but especially back then i
just loved attention
and so ian was just a lot better than me
at getting it so he was my natural rival
but then he was
he was just so charming that i got over
the jealousy and then it was just
charmed myself
and then two or three months later like
i don't know why like i guess
his apartment like was up the lease was
up or something and he
ended up moving in with me uh for like
two or three months or something
well we got we got really close really
fast and
i i was actually thinking about that
during so you know like you mentioned
the camp we're doing right now is adult
friendship
and um one of the things that we're kind
of doing during this camp is i think
reflecting on
friends uh we've made in the past and um
i was thinking about hours and like what
is it that
bonded us together super quickly
i mean like we became fast friends uh i
mean we became friends really fast
because i think like what
two months after knowing you like we
were living together
living together and working together ian
got me a job at the university of
florida
teaching um like basically teaching
foreign exchange students english
and um i don't know yeah i really don't
know and then then
then we spent like shortly after moving
in together he got a job and left the
country and we basically didn't see each
other for six years
seven seven years seven you guys text
every day through
saturday no we like honestly our
friendship uh
friendship was like on like a on
definite pause
um yeah for a long time we'd
occasionally catch up and
text but then as soon as we like started
hanging out again uh right after ian got
back into the country it was as if
nothing had happened you know just like
oh yeah this guy what's up perfect
that's great
yeah it's really crazy that was that was
crazy i actually i actually forgot about
that to be
complete yeah it's like as soon as i saw
this guy again it's like we picked up
right where we left off i mean
your breakup right yeah just like you
kept going
yeah um i'm sorry go ahead go ahead no
no i'm just going to dig in a little bit
more um
just about you guys individual
background so that's how you met um
yeah well you guys both have such good
chemistry and you're able to pick that
chemistry back up
like like nothing um do you guys have a
lot of the same
interest i mean i know i know a few of
your interests just
off the uh the top list that i saw over
on reddit but
um you guys want to explain to the
listeners a couple of your interests too
and how they overlap there because i
think
i i feel like with with the podcast
for this i'm always trying to point out
where people are the same and like a
different bridges that we can cap
because you can have nothing in common
and then
all of a sudden you're like wait you
like little plastic dragon ball z
figurines
and that's just like you know so i feel
like you guys have a lot of those your
chemistry is fantastic like i've said it
multiple times now
thanks man i appreciate it um
shade you i just i just always want to
defer to you i'm like yeah you you start
and then like once you pick up momentum
i'll just i'm like drafting on you like
it's a bicycle race or a triathlon or
something
that's great i love it um i like to
think of it as you're just writing on my
coattails but that's fine too
uh yeah i don't know i mean we were both
musicians
we both like we actually have an
incredibly similar backstory it's
it's bizarre like both of us almost
didn't graduate high school
and then had this weird come to jesus
moment and then went to college and then
ended up
becoming super academic afterwards we
were like both had disciplinary problems
and
um super creative super outgoing people
yeah i don't know i i know we were both
recording music a lot
what kind of music do you guys record
what what'd you get into
i i'm in a band so i do like uh
do it like indie electronic music the
band's called retrolux
and um it's it's me and a singer uh uh
a really good friend of mine she lives
in toronto now so we're we're split
apart
it's crazy all ian and i are split apart
as well so i'm in new york ian's in
boston so all of our
all of my like collaborations are remote
now which
i guess for most people now that's the
norm which is
interesting but um but yeah so i do like
the indie electronic and i think ian you
do uh you you were
it was inter the kind of music you did
was really interesting i thought
i i was i was kind of all over the place
um so i
my first band was actually a my first
band was actually like an on
a weird alternative band um and then
like the music i got really serious with
in high school was um
i was in a screamo band at like the peak
of uh like just the screamo phase and
like the
the mid-2000s who'd you listen to
screamo bandra oh my god
um yeah i'm i'm not i'm i'm aging and
like outing myself it's just like
slipping away it's so insignificant um
so i uh loved you know like just just
like all like the main
the main stuff i guess like the used
census fail from first to last
um thursday uh just like you know
you're the debate i don't want to say
like the basics but like that's pretty
much what it is it's like yeah it's like
the starter pack screamo for kids
yes i i fit in with all those i was
nodding my head furiously i've
purchased those shirts at hot topic
myself oh my god right yeah
just like oh yeah dude check out this
sweet new used shirt
yeah i would get i would get my school
clothes at either hot topic or warped
tour
when they were floating around see i
always wanted to be that
kid i like remember there was no hot
topic within driving distance of where i
grew up and i remember
being like 13 14 and demanding my mom
take me shopping so i could buy some
black clothes and we ended up in macy's
and i was like no it's not the right
kind like where's the
where's the cool black clothes and i
just didn't understand i didn't i never
even heard of hot topic you know that
was
i was opposing my mom's just don't
understand moms don't get it
come on god i remember i remember my mom
just being so worried about me going
through that phase too
like i remember one time i was watching
uh like
vh1s behind the music and it was about
like guns and roses
and it was the part where they're like
uh i don't know slash or axel i'm not
sure of their names just like yeah
and that's when the heroine started
shooting heroin yeah
my mom like turned off the tv and she's
like is this where you want to end up
is this is this where you want to end up
and i was like
i mean like no like no kid watches that
and like forget the music
like heroin i'm putting this guitar down
where i want to go like oh i can just
buy heroin i thought i had to be a
musician to do heroin
like what am i doing well that that's
super cool
i uh so i am a dj now i mean i'm
it's weird i haven't been a dj for a few
months now there's not exactly too many
gigs
um but i got into music myself i didn't
have much of a musical background just
kind of like
an obsession i always had headphones in
i was the walkman kid
um i had so many songs on my mp3 player
after the walkman
i always listened to music always going
to shows and stuff and then eventually
after high school i decided i was like
dude i i think i could do that thing
that that guy's doing up there
and i've been learning djing for um
nine years or now so and i and i
i learned you know you learn of course
some music and you kind of backhanded
learn a lot of weird audio stuff and you
music theory is so confusing to me but i
have a part inside me that understands
it whatever that means
um but it's so last couple years i've
been really exploring the musician side
i've been
trying to learn piano in my own way and
i try to you know
learn i eventually want to be a musician
is essentially where i'm at
with my djing but it's been a really
cool journey and it's really cool to
talk to other musicians i feel like
they always have great perspectives on
things have you tried producing at all
yeah um i i feel like i have just a ton
of adhd and so
a lot of times if it's not quick i don't
want to pull up the same project so if
sometimes i'll spend all day working on
something just the same kick
just looping it whatever but then the
next day i don't want to pull it back
up um that's that's how i was yeah yeah
but uh but i i do a good amount of edits
and stuff like for my dj sets i like
adding in a bunch of spoken word stuff
and adding you know making different
mashups in that way
i'll i'll lean more into producing as i
continue down the music world but
right now i'm just a novice learning
you and i kind of went like the the
opposite way a little bit because um and
and shay and i have had this
conversation too
like uh after the the screamo band um
broke up
after we broke up man the future is
screaming with each other
uh yeah it was it was uh i wanted to
make like a screamo pun but i just could
there's
i couldn't think of one that i wanted to
go with um but yeah like i started
making a
acoustic music and um did like a solo
project and then
music just started gradually getting
more and more electronic
and uh i was just kind of like i think
i'm going to go ahead and bow out like
it's just i can like become an engineer
basically or i can just like
respectfully say well it's been fun
and uh you know i kind of went back to
like shea had mentioned i was like maybe
i should just go
to college so
yeah that's good it's funny because that
was the exact opposite i was like
things are going electronic and i was
already recording a little bit in the
studio and i was like i think i could do
that and i started learning like midi
and all the programming stuff and that
was super fascinating and i wanted to
really dive in and learn that and it's
just so much easier
when you don't have a space to practice
it's just you in a room
with all your controllers you can just
do whatever and experiment and there's
like
very little opportunity cost because you
don't need someone to come in and track
you don't need a bassist you can just
play a synth bass i mean
obviously it doesn't sound the same but
you can make something that sounds
some some way hopefully somewhat
interesting but
yeah yeah i always like the uh uh duncan
trussell who's a comedian that i've
noted him through uh joe rogan's podcast
watching him on joe rogan's podcast he
had this sentence that i was like that
is so perfect he's like sometimes you
just need to uh
like be in a dark room with your
synthesizer just crying and drooling
over it
or something along those lines and i was
like yeah you know there is that
emotional release of just being able to
make some stuff
on an electrical thing you know just
some sound to come out of my fingers
from this midi controller
it's a really good thing i think it's a
there's a lot of healing in that in a
weird way
it's totally meditative 100 you know
especially sound design or like you you
like if you if you make your own synth
and then you're just like all right like
i spent 10 minutes like making a really
cool synth sound like now what am i
going to do with it and then you just
like explore what this new sound is like
and
if anything cool or catchy or you know
emotional can come out of that
i was going to ask um do you guys have
like a favorite song that you've written
and and like why i'll let you take that
jake
um well okay so i'm pretty new to
songwriting i
love songwriting i think it's the
coolest thing some days i'm like very
grandiose and i like to just to give
myself confidence i'm like i'm secretly
so good at songwriting
i think that i'm terrible but some days
i'm really in my head i'm like dude
you're really good
so um i write i write a lot of songs and
i'm still so
fresh like the last two years of really
actually trying to sit down and make
something
but i did have a couple months ago i had
this like spoken word
poetic piece that i had a few friends
over and i performed it for them just my
i basically
captivated them in my basement here and
said listen to my art
and i played it for them and they were
supportive of it so that is my favorite
yeah i locked him i shut the doors and
the dead bolt and everything
and uh so that's my favorite song right
now um and i don't even have a name for
it but it's just like the spoken word
piece
i love that yeah what about you shay
man i don't know you know like i m my
musical
my music background is split because i
either do
entirely electronic or just for myself
and for my close friends i'll write um
songs on guitar so i wrote a song for my
girlfriend recently and it's like the
first song i've written in like a year
or something where i'm like i actually
sing and like i write lyrics
because i never normally do that and uh
i guess right now it's my favorite
because it's so
i'm like writing lyrics and singing
yourself it's just so much more
emotionally close i guess that's what
you're talking about with the spoken
word and i'm just so used to
normally having um
i'm just so used to normally having
all of that outsourced to someone else
and like i can create like an emotional
canvas for someone else to imbue the
more specific meaning
and so for me to like actually write
down some lyrics and like my
girlfriend's really shy so i wrote this
song
called uh hide and seek and uh which is
so lame and i know it's been done
you know whatever you know but like what
are you gonna do so and
it's like the lyrics are just like oh
they're bored on creepy and i think like
a lot of love songs
they're like in the wrong light it's
creepy you know it's only if it's
if it's wanted but it's good but it's
just like talking about
um how uh
it's like you can go ahead and play hide
and seek but like i see you
like you you can try your best to hide
from me but it doesn't work like i see
who you are and like i love you
and like you can put up all these walls
and like try and hide yourself as
like in your own way whatever that means
for you but it doesn't matter
you know i'm here i see you like i love
you and uh
it was really impactful for me and for
our relationship and i don't know so
for i don't know really i don't know
that was really touching man
i don't even know this yeah that sounds
like a good song i think i i really like
the
that i see you i think that's something
that you know when you when you're
experiencing love in a relationship it's
something that you can
communicate through is this like no
really you can look them in the eye and
say i see you and it means something way
different than anybody else in the world
saying that same thing to you at that
moment
right yeah we we just uh so one of the
camps we did the immersions for the
podcast was uh into into microdosing
and as it turned out we ended up just
doing like a ton of macrodosing
um and all right wait okay do you want
to lay out the
this journey for me like how it went
i'm imagining the people haven't haven't
yet listened to
that episode so maybe leave them with a
little bit of well that that one's out
so they may have
uh but i won't give it i won't give too
much away but um
i mean yeah just um so i guess like a
side story
of this a spin-off of the the whole camp
was
me and uh me and my girlfriend were uh
laying in bed we decided we were gonna
do a macro dose i had never really done
like a high level acid trip and she had
never really done it at all
so we took some acid and put on
a huge playlist that was all of grizzly
bear's entire discography some andrew
bird and we put on
a big blank wall that she has in a room
projector
of planet earth with the audio off so it
was just grizzly bear and then planet
earth
and there was just a point where we
would just like stare at each other
sobbing and like every time like she
could see me looking at her
there was that that thing it's like no
we really see each other and that's
really kind of
what that the feelings that made that
song kind of come from
yeah wow i mean i imagine that's
probably something that when you guys
first set out to do that episode you
didn't think that that was going to be
something that would come out of it like
one of the most deep meaningful
situations
with your significant other oh sorry go
ahead
it's been crazy like we're constantly
surprised i think
with where what we think that it's going
to be like and then what it ends up
turning out
to be that's that's what i was going to
say too is like we every time and it's
been
really fun and i i hope that comes
through for anybody that listens to our
podcast but i mean like you know the
first one we started out doing we
we picked something really simple we
were like all right like we'll kind of
use this subject to also learn how to
just make a podcast so we won't
you know um really get in our own ways
too much and we did reality tv
and the goal was to watch like two hours
of reality tv every day and by the end
i was like watching the simple life like
you know writing in my journal like
oh i get it like paris hilton and nicole
ritchie they're like a metaphor for the
way like aristocrats like rule over and
make life harder for middle america i
i get it so it just it goes on like
these
these whole um
like there's like all of these like
thoughts and feelings that just kind of
come out of left field and like a lot of
it has been
really teaching us more about ourselves
i think too like
yeah the reality tv one especially like
there was this this big question that
uh really caught us by surprise which
we we just weren't expecting at all and
it was the question of whether or not
the criticism of reality tv because i
feel like everyone criticizes
reality tv as it's like you know it's
garbage tv or whatever
and we we we started to wonder if the
criticism of reality tv itself was
maybe sexist like it was or based in
some kind of gender bias because
a lot of the the tv they're talking
about are is like reality tv geared at
women
and that was this weird reflection that
seems like it seems obvious to us now
but at the time
it was like wait are we like being
really sexist all of a sudden like we
didn't oh yeah
we didn't even understand it because we
were like haha reality tv it's so dumb
and then we're like oh man this is like
a medium that's like
targeted towards women i mean they
self-describe like and they market
themselves
sometimes as trash tv but still
even even considering that it was it was
a question that like all of a sudden was
like
eye-opening and shocking and like we
really had to pump the brakes for a
minute
during the immersion yeah that was that
was an interesting moment and i mean
uh i was it your friend that brought up
the point as well that um
we had interviewed a friend of chez who
kind of brought up that like
no one talks about reality tv shows for
men the same way like viva la van
and jackass like these shows that are
just objectively
way worse uh in terms of jus the
stupidity that they kind of project or
capture
and and those just kind of get ignored
and like all the focus is on
you know real housewives and um you know
the bachelor
right yeah that is that's a super
interesting perspective because i don't
think i would have thought of either of
those things the
men's reality tv show i mean i grew up
watching cky and all those guys just
like drop kick each other in the face
as a teenager and it's interesting
because it makes you kind of think
you know it's almost just a reminder of
not everything is for everyone
i know that sounds so overly obvious but
like we we
consume things that are in like the the
popular
media as if it's like this is what
everyone should like and it's just one
layer and it's sometimes you got to be
reminded of like
when you actually indulge in it and
you're it's not that it sucks
it's just that it's not your thing a lot
of the times
yeah we ended up we ended up talking
about that as well like um one of the
one of the
i don't know if i would call it like a
realization or just conversation that we
had had shape but it was that uh that
like
uh who was it schoenberg that idea like
oh if it's for art it's not for all
and if it's uh for all then it's not art
and um we just kind of talked about like
the atomization of culture in general
and like we're at this area of like
hyperspecificity
to the extent that like nothing is for
everyone anymore
um so it's like in that sense like
everything is art
for someone in some capacity so i mean
it was it
it really took us down a rabbit hole but
it was super interesting to think about
this thing that's
relatively ubiquitous in like american
culture so it was
a blast to think about for two weeks it
was
also just shocking because we didn't see
that coming we thought like the
the premise of the show is to check our
biases and our preconceptions
like that's like that's the whole idea
we're re-educating ourselves that's the
point
but i think even then i thought we we
still kind of thought we were going to
go in
be like just you know like go through
the motions like try and see other
perspectives but then we were like
actually shocked
to see this depth in this in this art
form that
is i don't know always ridiculed and
always thought of as as a lower common
denominator
but i don't know it now it just feels to
me more akin to
a weird like really progressive folk art
where it's like hyper in your face but
it's
it is kind of for everyone it's like
it's like graffiti it's aggressive
and it's loud um but it's entertaining
in its own way
you know yeah yeah that's so cool like
you just by diving into the culture for
for two weeks you're you're like oh okay
i get this this much more
have you guys changed a lot of so just
from when you first had the conceptual
idea of like oh we could do this and
and we're inquisitive and we're willing
to try these things whatever
um just then until now um have you guys
like changed your approach towards how
you're going to handle
the upcoming episodes and the upcoming
um um
immersions i'll let you take this one in
[Laughter]
that's that's a really great tough
question um
you know what's so interesting is like
when we first started these camps i was
asking
impossible questions so with every camp
we try to give ourselves like
some a guiding question to help us think
about it moving forward so we're not
just kind of
groping blindly through the subject and
mine have been
apps like really difficult like my first
question was um
shay what was my first question i
already forgot it i think it was like
how does reality tv reflect the
zeitgeist
that was the that was the podcast one
podcast one was what uh like
how did yeah what what are p how do
podcasts reflect the zeitgeist of our
age i think reality tv was key in
reality tv
art can it be art right yeah uh
microdosing was um when we did
microdosing it was can micro dosing
uh help you um achieve transcendence and
thus
also uh like uh
not support what's the one i'm looking
for um i guess help you
reach self-actualization and then for
makeup camp
it was i think it was like what is
beauty or something
yeah so it's like that my question
started really broadly and like as we've
continued to do this i've kind of
realized that like i really need to
narrow my focus because i've just been
super overwhelming myself um and it's
it's kind of proven for good comedy
because like halfway through i'm like
why did i do this
yeah you're like writing a book yeah i
know i mean more or less that's what it
was like
um so like yeah but shea what about you
how how i've changed honestly uh
i think i feel more confident now just
from this experience
to try and believe something for a
little while with the understanding that
i can be wrong
in that belief and then and revisit it
later i think starting out i was really
afraid to commit to an idea about
something i don't already know
a lot about which i think is a good
thing in some ways
i don't think it's good to to commit so
firmly
to a belief without having a lot of
grounding to it
but i do think that for me was a little
bit disabling
and i think now i i can proceed with
some confidence in some conviction in my
understanding of things with the
understanding that they can always be
revisited that i'm
gonna be wrong regardless of how much
conviction i put in it
or not i'm sometimes i'm gonna be wrong
so now at least i can
take a deep breath and continue with
some confidence
and then now just be like okay well that
was a wrong idea like i i messed up
and now i can just acknowledge that and
move on and there's no
catastrophe you know now i'm just i'm
still here
yeah i like that that's a great point go
on
going i was just gonna say too like
maybe the
the most beneficial or the most fun part
about this project and shay
i'm not sure if you would agree or not
maybe you would is that it it's been
great to kind of help me
approach my like cognitive dissonance
abstractly
like to be able to kind of see it as
something that i'm trying to dissect for
an audience as opposed to just like
something that's fundamental to who i am
as a person
um and that's when we kind of talked
about like we've been learning a lot
about ourselves
it's like instead of you know you get
into an argument with someone
and uh i know they say something like um
oh you know well all lives matter and
then like there's just kind of that
instinct where you're like
it just kicks in and you're like wow
[__] um
um not that we've been doing getting
into stuff like that but like you know
beliefs that i've had
and then i'm having these experiences
and like i'm having different uh
opinions about them and it's different
from what i thought
and then just kind of being able to like
you know feel that and then dissect it
and be like
what is this coming from um how can i
explain this to people and that's really
helped just kind of
um kind i i don't know like
dissect the self and be like oh okay
like
this is why i feel this way about this
thing that's interesting hmm
yeah that's that's brilliant man i
because
you know that's why like what your
guys's podcast what you guys are doing
really caught my eye is like i think
right now especially in the world as
individuals we all need to kind of take
a look at why we think we know
so much about what we think we know you
know it's such a
such a weird weird on so many weird it's
not even the word there needs to be a
new word beyond weird
or what's going on everywhere in the
world right now like we can't seem to
make sense of it like
we're yelling over each other's heads
and between each other's legs but we
think we're having like a
logistical argument or something so i
think it's really cool that you guys are
taking a look
in and like oh what what do i know about
this now and what do i know
after emerging i'm immersing emerging
myself in it for two weeks um i think
that
so for me exactly because i kind of
gained this over the last couple years i
kind of gained this like remain in
disbelief
um uh sort of thing when i'm hosting the
podcast i really try to like
just be open to whatever and really just
like almost believe
at that moment anyway everything
anybody's telling me at that moment
so i can feel what it really feels like
and
through more episodes after the episodes
and a couple weeks later after i've had
time to sit on the content
to sit on the conversations i can find
areas where i'm like
you know i don't actually believe that
or um no i i feel more stern of where
i'm at it's almost
the same thing that you guys were saying
is it's almost solidifying who i
am and desolidifying who i'm not in in
strange
particular ways yeah i do really like
that too
it's uh i don't know i love it it's such
a
i feel like it's like a beginner's mind
right it's like you're not it's like the
student's mind like trying to
continually
continuously just remain open to
experience and
i'm sure that i'm sure you learn a lot
more with that mindset i imagine
you have to yeah can we can we take a
side road and talk about like
can you think of something that each of
you how did you get to where you're
even open to this because i think
there's a lot of people who
to even mold into the beginner's mind
i'll say that the first 25 years of my
life i mean it was i was always fairly
growth mindset i was pretty
um like self-determined in those sort of
ways
but i don't think that i was as open to
that beginner's mind as i am now i'm
just like a total infant with new
conversations now i'm like yeah just
just teach me and i think that that
awareness like noticing
where we're sometimes a no doll or we
think we have something figured out or a
subject
i think that's a huge great starting
point for anybody who's maybe on the
edge of like all right i'm going to try
to get this
beginner's mind going for myself so what
do you guys have on that
beginner's mind how did you get there
i feel like ian's better at this if i'm
asking the weird intricate questions
no i mean i actually i um are we able to
swear on here by the way because i threw
it in [__]
man i mean flip yeah just so you're
confused
because i i [__] love this question i
think this is such a great question and
um
like right off the bat there are like
three things i want to say to kind of
answer this question because
it's it's like um three cars kind of
trying to drive out of a tunnel
simultaneously so i'm i'm gonna try to
walk through this in a way that's like
logical and sensible so i mean
um immediately based on your question
about just like
you know trying to be open to stuff like
that's that's like the the the
conversation
mindset where you know if you look at
i mean every sentence is essentially
like a thesis right like that in of
itself like is
is a claim um it's hot it's cold like
there's an idea in there that and you're
trying to
you know like solidify it as a a fact
about an objective fact about the world
um because in a way like you know you
feeling a certain way
is an objective fact and then another
person can you know subjectively
interpret that and be like
well no it's a little it's a little cold
um i don't really think you felt that
way
um because everything that you say is an
interpretation
on behalf of another person so you do if
you want to do something like this you
have to kind of suspend that disbelief
that you had said and you could be like
okay like absolutely
i can imagine myself feeling that way
i'm cold but i could see why you're hot
um so it's just and that's something i
feel like i learned in like linguistics
uh when i took a linguistics courses in
college and stuff like that and it's
just like
oh like language is just an attempt to
kind of construct reality
like i get it i get it now like we're
all just kind of
it's all a fairy tale that we live
in and we're trying to like kind of
communicate that story to another person
so it's like we're all kind of it's it's
almost like i imagine um
if i were to try to make it like a more
physical metaphor everyone's kind of
living in a bubble
um but the bubbles are um porous so it's
like you you kind of try to
uh intermix that uh
interpretation of the world with another
person and then like you try to come to
a mutual understanding of of where you
both are
um and then the the second one and i'll
be really short was um
i just remember reading and this is
super cheesy but i read an einstein
of uh bio i read einstein what the [__]
i read a biography of einstein and uh he
wrote um in a letter to his first wife
like may we never lose our childlike
sense of curiosity about the world
and uh i was like oh that's why he was a
[__] genius because he approached
everything
with a child's mind and was just like
you know i don't
fully understand how this works um
and i think that like it's so easy to
kind of and it's not you know it's it's
not even easy it's it's the
and shea and i've talked about this
during asset camp it's the default mode
network
like it's a survival thing like um it's
it's biological and we forget that we're
animals sometimes because we're higher
order animals but like
our instinct to immediately categorize
things as like yes no good bad hot cold
big small
um it was a was a biological survival
technique so that we would be like okay
tall grass equals big lion
um you know dark water equals bad to
drink um
bitter fruit equals diarrhea um
and that just kind of grew and expanded
into
you know like modern society so it's
like we still have that that lizard
brain that uh
is quick to judge um but we forget that
like we don't necessarily need that for
you know ideas or human relationships so
that was very long-winded and i
apologize but that's that's my best
attempt to answer like a really
difficult but fun question that was
valiant me i loved it that was great
yeah yeah your turn i was now
i feel the eyes they're pointing at me
now
um i don't know i really like ian's
answer
uh i'll just i'll just say ditto and
then
[Laughter]
no but i think what ian said about the
kind of like the psycho-linguistic
approach to it
uh really resonated with me as well
because i i studied i studied like
linguistics kind of through like a back
road like i just like started
learning other languages and then
learning a ton about grammar and then
kind of through
grammar ended up learning a lot about
linguistics and then kind of more like
this psycho-linguistic approach
but i think i think what you get when
you when you kind of take that approach
and you open up your mind
you realize that you like all of
language and like every word
like kind of to bounce off what you're
saying in every word
is just an attempt at encapsulating an
idea somehow
so you say the word couch and well what
exactly is couch like there is no one
couch there is a range of things
in which uh something could be a couch
so you know even that's fluid which
you know it seems like such a concrete
idea but you know obviously there's gray
zones and every
there's gray zones with everything so i
and and when you learn other languages
you see
that an idea that is so obvious and
distinguished
in one language may be open-ended
and like blurry in another and then you
realize
that the framework for your
interpretation of everything
is is just based on a lot of you're just
you're what you've been exposed to so
far especially your language i think
this is like a little bit of like the
superior warf hypothesis that like your
language determines the way you
you view the world um which which i like
and i also don't like but
i don't know i think coming from that
perspective you you start to see that
everything you know to be something is
really
it's just an approximation anyway so
it's right
yeah so as right as you can be or want
to be it's like
ultimately how much does it matter you
know whatever we're all going to die and
be wrong about tons of things so who
cares
um just just to kind of yeah like um the
stuff that shay
was talking about uh initially was like
linguistics 101 is
is one of the first and i think everyone
should have to take like linguistics
101. like i mean can you imagine like
being given this tool and you're never
really taught how to use it like
you've mastered it to an extent you know
and it's just like
like you're using it well enough but
maybe you're expelling like
um too much energy to to use it
correctly but
like there's that idea in linguistics of
uh you know sense and reference
and um you know when i say cat it's like
the sense is you know okay
whiskers tail um fur claws
uh etc like those are your senses and
like the reference is like oh i had a
cat named hobie
um in second grade and uh it's simple
when you get into like concrete
uh constructs or ideas like you know cat
car couch like shea was mentioning but
then it gets so much more complicated
when you get into abstract ideas like
you know love
democracy justice fairness and then
everybody's
sense and reference is so different so i
mean i almost feel like
and this is you know maybe like a um
this is like a criticism of
post-modernism too right that like we
have to first before we can even have
the argument we have to
establish a definition but i think
there's benefit to that i think there's
benefit to both people being like you
know
especially now with a lot of the
division we see in america it's like all
right well like what exactly is your
sense of
justice and then like what is your
reference like what are you basing this
off of
um so you know especially with like the
older generation like well life's not
fair
it's like where does that come from like
where the [__] that's
the answer so that's it
yeah that's uh that's great man i really
like where both of you guys took that
because you know it's it's
we're out of time especially with the
internet and technology we're kind of
just forced to
to look at our our perceptions and we're
kind of forced to
i don't know if we're we're trying to
make them all work
you know like we're this big experiment
of like of trying to make everybody's
different views because
we're not trying to discover like the
truth as much as we're all trying to
like
explain the truths that feel right to us
as individuals
as we go every day um
yeah it's super interesting i so i have
never learned another language
i would like to at some point um my
my fiancee is i say fiance weirdly
because i just recently got
engaged so it still it doesn't roll off
the top congratulations
thank you yes thank you i appreciate
that uh very pumped about it but
um she wants to eventually learn spanish
and now there's just so many different
ways
to learn it that i think it's going to
be cool when people are able to
learn different languages and really
realize how
we we see reality so differently like
when i started learning anything about
like eastern world philosophy or any
like buddhism or hinduism
there was like you know dao and these
certain words that like
when i heard the death when i heard
certain people alan watts for example
talk about these things
i'm like i don't know what you're saying
like there's not even like
a setting for the the subject that
you're talking on but then once i
started listening more and more
i imagine this is a little bit kind of
how our brains learn language
it's like you start to understand the
concept that you didn't have an arena
for um you didn't have like a a practice
room that even existed for you to
to go in and understand the things
that's super confusing but um
learning language i think is is a super
cool thing and i imagine what it does to
our brains is a lot of
um this probably sends off similar
signals and similar things of when we
completely change our perception of what
we thought we knew you know yeah
and i'll i'll like kind of humble brag
for shay here like shay is
shay's a brilliant uh linguist i mean he
really
i love the way he thinks about language
so like i you know i i warn anybody who
wants to get into a debate with him
about it
because he thinks about it a lot and
shay i know you speak spanish
uh you speak a little bit of swedish you
speak french um
is there anything else in that like
swiss army mouth of yours
no not that i speak but i i did take a
really keen interest into esperanto for
a little while
and uh for anyone who's like a true
language nerd uh
they're excited that i'm mentioning
probably their their favorite
constructed language but uh
but um yeah no it's it's really
interesting because what you were just
describing
especially about like the having like
the space to understand that idea
uh one of the guys we talked to uh in
microdosing camp he's a science writer
uh for the max planck institute he had
this really awesome idea and i
and i'll be totally honest i know i
don't like i i only
i can tell my understanding of this idea
is still pretty nation like i don't
it's not totally part of me so forgive
me if i don't explain it in the best way
but his his thesis was basically you
can't teach someone you can't talk to
someone
something about i'm sorry you can't talk
to someone about something they don't
already know or is that you can't teach
them
that they they have to already have a
pretty good understanding of it
for you for the for the language to make
sense to them at all and i think that's
basically what you're saying like if you
can't if you don't have the
understanding the word isn't going to
make sense
you know the the language has to follow
the i don't know i don't i don't know
exactly
the experience the cognition something
the understanding fundamentally
yeah yeah in my head i like to call it i
i think i i
think visually and so a lot of times in
my head it's it's the
setting the arena it's almost like a
almost like
the beginning of the conversation here's
what we're talking about um but it's
it's it's so hard to pinpoint i do know
um i understand what you are saying
though
and i think that's a great place i think
that a lot of a lot of our arguments now
in the you know like the crazy news
world america whatever america is doing
right now um
i think it's it's a lot of that people
not understanding that they're
in different arenas like we we're like
in different stadiums
yelling at each other and thinking that
like the sound is going over the top of
them and we're having a perfect
conversation
it's just just madness so what you guys
are doing is super cool um so
what tell me about the future plans that
you guys have
um i know right now you mentioned you're
working on adult friendships but
what's what's the plan to lean into how
do you guys come up with your
with your new subjects well i think
really we just try
right now we're trying to think of of a
couple different approaches
uh what's interesting and and kind of
use universally
relatable to some people so i think the
friendship one is everyone right now
especially with
with kovid they're a lot of people are
really struggling to to find
meaningful connection and i ourselves
included like i spend most of my time
with my girlfriend now which is not how
i ever used to be i'm a really social
person
and so now like investigating what
friendship is the idea there is just
as universal we also have uh i think
like this part of like this like
punk rock screamo band side of us that
like wants to really push some
boundaries
so uh we have a uh should we talk about
our our big plans ian for uh
for our next camp or is that uh this
one's been a little contentious with
people like we're we're
we've grown hesitant to talk about it
because i mean i guess it's a sensitive
issue
um for for a lot of people so i mean how
like are you are you going to get
uncomfortable if we talk about like
demons and
and like uh evocation summon them let's
do this
i have a ouija board right here i was
just doing a ritual last night
no i i'm all ears i'm supremely open to
new experiences and new knowledge i'm
definitely want to hear all about this
well i mean my listeners are also open
they're not going to like come to try to
cancel you guys or
anything are really cool we'll wait to
cancel us until we have a couple
episodes out
a couple more out but i mean you know
you nailed it that's what we're gonna do
we're gonna spend
uh two weeks um every day
trying to summon demons um and we're
gonna
try and find as many traditions that
have evocation
uh practices and just try them all
with the the kind of the background the
background ideas that
we identify as agnostic atheists some
you know somewhere in that area
and if we really are so strong in these
convictions
then then this shouldn't be scary for us
and it shouldn't be there
there should be nothing to worry about
so we're effectively putting our money
where our mouth is uh and i think some
to some people it's it's
it's it's terrifying for them because
they truly believe that there'll be
something there
for me it feels almost like i feel bad
because i feel like
i'm i'm making fun of someone but i
really want to come at it with the
perspective of like no i really want to
try this and i really want to believe it
which is different from ian because
we've we've already uh
we've done a segment on this already
like in anticipation for the episode
called ignorance in a bottle where we
talk about our preconceptions before we
do any research on it so we don't kind
of spoil our ignorance we keep our
ignorance preserved
and ian's ian has some reticence like he
does he's already afraid
uh so i have i and my thing isn't
necessarily like a religious thing as
well like
my thing is you know you you spend 32
years with your brain and you you
begin to develop an understanding of how
it works and like i know what i need to
avoid and like i know what uh like
you i know how to outsmart my my
impulses
essentially and um i have an extremely
overactive imagination so it's like i
don't watch horror movies
i'm not a big fan of gore like i i avoid
certain things i've got you know like a
pretty a relatively addictive
personality so they're like there's
certain things i'm like okay
i shouldn't i shouldn't [__] with this
so with demon summoning camp it's like i
already know i'm gonna be like
like any bump in the night any like
shadow
cast i'm gonna be like oh [__] it's the
devil that's the
they're here oh they demons me so it's
just like i know that like
it's gonna be like that for me for two
weeks and then maybe
for weeks after i mean like you're
talking to a guy and like i will totally
telling myself here
in high school i saw i think it was the
exorcism of emily rose
and like i was so freaked out that like
i was next
because i was like i don't know why i
was just such like a
sweet supple boy for the for the demons
i like snuck into my parents room and
slept
um at the foot of their bed because i
guess satan doesn't possess you if
you're with mommy and daddy
like i don't know oh man i do i
paranormal activity had that same effect
on me that was it's funny looking at it
now it seems like a corny movie to watch
but it's
at that time i'm like wait like a
security camera movie
and is that is that real are they were
they sleeping and the covers came off
you
don't really know i think that's a
really cool cool idea um i think that
you'll you'll you'll be surprised at how
it's almost like a lot of these subjects
when you go into them you think you're
learning about
this aspect of that subject but you're
almost are forced to learn about
something completely different
within the exact same experience um i i
think that
even just observing you guys should also
i'm sure you do
um you know take notes of like of your
fear every day like are you
looking over your shoulder a little more
are you you know
because i think even those words um
i'm not sure what i think about all that
myself but but even those words
you know have like
meanings that pop things into your mind
that you weren't planning on thinking
about that day for sure
you know so that's i mean but but we
also play grand theft auto and we don't
go
driving our cars around and killing
hookers and stuff so
um yeah that's that's super cool how did
you guys
land on that one is really just the
putting your money where your mouth is
like we
you know here's what we know strongly
what we feel strongly
let's try to push up against that or try
to um
even just like put a megaphone on that i
yeah right well i think the idea was at
first we were gonna do
we were looking at um different
religious beliefs
uh as atheists and then we looked at
some of them and
you know like some of them just don't
feel like you can't you can't do islam
like i feel like
um there's no there's you kind of you
kind of can't because i mean like
just so touchy really quickly and then
and then back out like one of the
i remember um when we first met uh i was
before i got you the job at the english
language institute um i had a bunch of
uh muslim students and it was ramadan so
i observed ramadan with them because
they were like oh we're hungry we're
sleepy we're
thirsty and i was like all right i'm
going to observe ramadan with you
and under the pretend set if i don't
complain
you can't complain and we we learn the
lesson
so i think necessarily yeah i think
you're right that there's not
necessarily like you can't just
you know convert but you can uh
observe or participate in some of the uh
some of the orthopraxy
right yeah i just mean i specifically
just mean uh
i don't i don't want to be a tourist in
someone's religion especially a religion
that in our country uh
there are people who are targeted for
those beliefs you know in in a dangerous
way
so um so i you know i we want to avoid
that and we want to be sensitive to
people who have
who have ex suffered um
so so we we were thinking about those
and
those religions see and christianity
seems like such an easy target these
days and
uh you know judaism has also had you
know its fair share of anti-semitism
so then we're like what about satanism
and then we're like what do we do with
satanism and then eventually this idea
of like demon summoning and then we're
just like well that's really all we're
interested in that's that's like that's
the headline for
for satanism anyway let's just jump
straight to that and then we almost kind
of reverse engineering we're like well
okay well
pagans and witches do this as well from
from the little we understand so far we
haven't started the camp yet so
uh we're still you know we're still
pretty ignorant about it um
but we now we understand that there's
like other traditions
that do evocation that's not you know
that's not even necessarily a christian
belief it predates christianity i'm
pretty sure
for a long time so uh we're gonna try
all these things you know and just see
kind of where it takes us and hopefully
you know we get like some we we get the
punk rock energy going for some other
people too because it does feel kind of
counterculture and it is fun
to relive this like rebellious younger
side while also
genuinely trying to learn yes yes as a
fellow
um young man who was emo and wore lots
of
tight black pants growing up himself i'm
with you boys
um i i think that that right now you
know i keep saying right now especially
but
we're we're kind of at this weird edge
in our civilization where we're not able
to
have important conversations because
they're weirdo like
they make us uncomfortable so we don't
want to talk about them like uh
i mean i even noticed i had a
conversation with my with my friend
who's black
um on a podcast a couple episodes ago
and basically like try to talk about the
race thing
and i was just my foot was in my mouth i
was stumbling over the words i was like
dude i don't know how to do this
like this is this is weird um it's all
it's
that's a whole nother complicated issue
when it comes to those things but i
think that
the things that we're so solid about we
should
defend them and the things that defend
them by like
uh challenging our own beliefs about
them and like reassuring ourselves and
the beliefs and the things that we
don't know much about we should explore
i think that's that's fantastic
and i think that's part of the reason we
were so excited about this subject or
just this project was um
and uh i mean feel free to like back me
up add on or subtract anything but like
i i think it was kind of this idea like
you know there are enough podcasts
that tell people you know um what to
think like what if what about a podcast
that like shows people how to unlearn
and relearn um and like make it fun and
because like i mean
we i do think learning is fun like not
to be like
you know an episode of reading rainbow
but um like
learning new things is exciting because
you're like oh like this is a whole
like i'm i'm adding to my existence
and to my uh you know understanding of
what it means to be human like i'm
enriching
uh my already relatively rich life like
this is this is
great that's like the best thing you
could do yeah
yeah and especially i feel like in the
era of
twitter where the the loudest opinion
regardless of its validity or how
thought out it is
gets the most attention we're trying to
ideally come out thought differently
we're trying to not just say whatever
comes out and just be controversial
for the sake of controversial we're
trying to be controversial for the sake
of
challenging preconceptions our own
especially but challenging anyone else
who might share those same
preconceptions
and not just be a loud controversial
figure but be
allowed thoughtful controversial figure
you know i mean there really isn't a lot
of that there's
there's a lot of people who just like
getting mad at something and then like
if they can get two people behind them
that say
yeah then they're really super empowered
right
it's good um guys i think we're getting
up here in time
i think that it was a fantastic uh intro
to your podcast and what you guys are
doing and to you
as individuals i know that i'm
definitely i checked out a couple
episodes
um and did a little did a little
research and checked it out i enjoy your
guys's energy
um i think you're you're both pretty
damn funny
um i think that the the quality of the
podcast
is pretty good too um i like the the
little inserts and the
the sounds and it's just great it's well
ran i really really appreciated it and
so i thought it was really cool that you
guys
reached back out to me when i said hey
so
i'm glad that you came on today guys
thank you so much man
this was such a great conversation and
uh yeah i really we really
both we were so excited when uh you
contacted us because we listened to a
couple episodes and i don't know the
vibe is just awesome man
i really appreciate what you're doing as
well so thank you so much
i i was going to say something nice but
i forgot
i'll wait and you think of something
okay just give me a second
oh man i had it then i was like
listening to shay and i'm like
how about instead you just uh give the
listeners all of you guys's info so if
they want to go
follow you guys podcasts write this so
camp reeducation because
they find that on spotify all those yeah
you can find it you can find camper
education
anywhere you can listen to podcasts just
plug it up we'll be there waiting for
you with open arms we're so excited to
have you we just can't wait to
you know bring you into camp um we also
have a website campaignyeducation.com um
we absolutely love getting suggestions
we have a page where if you listen to an
episode and we got something wrong
or if you just want to uh insult share i
in a really funny way
we would love to read that on the air
and crack each other up so
um feel free to do that as well am i
missing anything
no just i think you forgot to direct
them to mostly
point the insults in your direction i'm
far too sensitive i cannot really handle
that so thank you
okay yes bring it on i'm uh
in also just since i'm part of this
conversation i'm emotional and soft so
please don't insult me
[Laughter]
our beautiful boy jacob is off limits
okay yes
i'm awful in limits uh cool guys this
was super cool um i hope to stay in
contact with you guys once in a while i
really think what you're doing is
is super cool and uh i hope we get some
new listeners for you out of this
experience awesome
thank you and likewise i wish i sounded
as smart on my show as
i was able to sound on yours but uh shay
doesn't give me any layups he's just
like
the kunta kinte he just smacks them all
out i'm like come on man
yeah i i edit how ian however ian
however smart ian sounds that's
how i edit him to sound
all right all right fellas well have a
good rest of your day and uh i can't
wait for the next episode of camp for
education
all right thank you brother thanks again
man it was a great time yeah
see you later
so should we are we are we actually
leaving or we just
knowledge is power
you